{
    "id": "fa8c2b0a7e3442b48bc512805cf16a3f",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I find the key I …………………….. it to you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will give",
                "would give",
                "would have given"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………… hard, you would get the first rank.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could / might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "study",
                "studied",
                "had studied"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she finds out we ………………………. in trouble.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If it is late, we ……………………….. out now.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cannot go",
                "could not go",
                "could not have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. non-stop, your health will suffer.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "worked",
                "had worked"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I …………………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can find",
                "could find",
                "could have found"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ……………………….. that dog alone, it wouldn’t have bitten you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "leave",
                "had left",
                "left"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had listened to me, you …………………………….. in trouble.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not be",
                "would not be",
                "would not have been"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………. guests tomorrow, I will not be able to come with you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "will have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. a billionaire, how would you spend your money?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I …………………………. this.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will not tolerate",
                "would not tolerate",
                "would not have tolerated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had asked me, I …………………………. you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will tell",
                "would tell",
                "would have told"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}